<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>ICIQ - Information, Computation, Intelligence and Quantum</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href=""/>
 <updated>2017-06-24T21:13:48+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://iciq.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>ICIQ Community</name>
   <email>iciqproject@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Integrating with Reddit on /r/QuantumInformation</title>
   <link href="/2017/06/24/integrate-with-reddit.html"/>
   <updated>2017-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://iciq.github.io/2017/06/24/integrate-with-reddit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a trial, ICIQ is testing an integrated connection to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; which has some interesting features to allow open-source developments and high engagements. Our trial subreddit is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/quantuminformation&quot;&gt;/r/QuantumInformation&lt;/a&gt;. Please voice up if you have a good idea on how to make it work better than now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features that have been enabled by some programming works in the past months in hoping to make it work better than other online groups:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic moderations for spams, flairing, reminders and other administration works. The CSS style and wiki configurations have been polished to a distinguished shape and satisfy our basic needs in discussing problems and sharing progresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic posting on periodical discussion threads. We will have a Yearly discussion thread to be automatically posted on July 1st. Hopefully, this kind of threads can go monthly or even weekly as we have more members. This feature could be helpful to satisfy both general audience and exports for their needs on different channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic YouTube videos posting from some well-known research entities. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/QuantumInformation/wiki/index#wiki_youtube_and_blog_channels_to_be_automatically_posted_on_this_sub&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; page for suggesting more channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic posting new posts from this website to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/quantuminformation&quot;&gt;/r/QuantumInformation&lt;/a&gt; subreddit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic tweeting short messages to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iciq_project&quot;&gt;ICIQ project twitter page&lt;/a&gt; so that people following the ICIQ twitter account can easily get updates from the subreddit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features to be implemented in the near future:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic posting updates from community blogs or other websites of the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic tweeting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/quantuminformation&quot;&gt;/r/QuantumInformation&lt;/a&gt; updates to other social media interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hope is to integrate our &lt;a href=&quot;https://iciq.github.io&quot;&gt;ICIQ&lt;/a&gt; efforts which are mainly focusing on open-source projects and self-organized small group studies for quantum information science (see our collaborations with &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliaquantum.github.io&quot;&gt;JuliaQuantum&lt;/a&gt; organization as well) to a broader social network and facilitate research efforts in the cutting-edge information community by using modern IT tools and enhancing interactions of clustered groups of people with knowledge and passions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested to participate, just join the subreddit and comment with your updates and opinions. We are definitely open to see what you think about this trial and what you can do to advance the scientific program and the ecosystem in a broad sense! Welcome to invite more people to join us, when you truly value this initiative–success or learn something more from failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Summer group study on Quantum Chaos, Randomness, Scrambling and Scientific Computing Basics</title>
   <link href="/2017/05/20/group-study-on-chaos-randomness-and-scientific-programming-basics.html"/>
   <updated>2017-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://iciq.github.io/2017/05/20/group-study-on-chaos-randomness-and-scientific-programming-basics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As before, we will have a [summer study plan for this year(http://i2000s.github.io/en/2017/05/20/2017-summer-study.html).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed main topics:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chaos, randomness and scrambling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic skills for scientific programming (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cquic.github.io/summer17-computing-workshop/&quot;&gt;CQuIC computing workshop&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time is from May 19th to Aug 9th (flexible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested to participate, comment below &lt;a href=&quot;http://i2000s.github.io/en/2017/05/20/2017-summer-study.html&quot;&gt;Xiaodong Qi’s post&lt;/a&gt; or post your peer reviews onto our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cquic.github.io/summer17-computing-workshop/resources/followup-projects.html&quot;&gt;followup projects&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, our telecom ports are all booked, and hence remote connections seems impossible this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a fruitful summer of 2017! Comment below to let us know if you would like to organize similar public community events for the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Summer group study on Advanced Topics in Quantum Optics II</title>
   <link href="/2016/05/27/group-study-on-advanced-topics-in-quantum-optics-II.html"/>
   <updated>2016-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://iciq.github.io/2016/05/27/group-study-on-advanced-topics-in-quantum-optics-II</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.wiley.com/product_data/coverImage300/73/35274070/3527407073.jpg&quot;  scale=&quot;95%&quot;    align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;laser cooling and optical pumping&quot;   /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, we will have a summer study plan for this year: &lt;a href=&quot;http://i2000s.github.io/en/2016/05/26/2016-summer-study-on-quantum-optics-II.html&quot;&gt;Advanced Topics in Quantum Optics II&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed main topics:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optical pumping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laser cooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matrix/tensor product state representation of many-body systems (let’s see if time permits)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time is from June 1st to July 29th (flexible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested to participate, comment below &lt;a href=&quot;http://i2000s.github.io/en/2016/05/26/2016-summer-study-on-quantum-optics-II.html&quot;&gt;Xiaodong Qi’s post&lt;/a&gt; or post your academic question on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/home/channel/quantumoptics&quot;&gt;Quantum Optics forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a fruitful summer of 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Enable comments and forums</title>
   <link href="/2016/05/25/Enable-comments-and-forums.html"/>
   <updated>2016-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://iciq.github.io/2016/05/25/Enable-comments-and-forums</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now you can add comments and discuss sophisticated questions on our topical forums on this site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been made possible by reprogramming the site with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and integrating with &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; functionalities. Comments are enabled on some pages, like this one (see bottom). We have also created a couple of initial forums. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/home/channel/quantuminformationandcomputing&quot;&gt;Quantum Information and Computing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/home/channel/quantumoptics&quot;&gt;Quantum Optics&lt;/a&gt; – this will be used for the coming summer group study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, you should be able to add new forums to this site by simply adding the Disqus forum name to the configuration file (_config.yml) of the source code. To add a forum or participate discussions using the two functions, you may be asked by the plugin to create/login the Disqus account using your email/social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this helps! And, yeah, comment below if you have questions or suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
